freemius.com 2019-06-07

# Privacy Policy – Freemius

Freemius, Inc. (the “Company”) is committed to maintaining robust privacy protections for its users. Our Privacy Policy (“Privacy Policy”) is designed to help you understand how we collect, use and safeguard the information you provide to us and to assist you in making informed decisions when using our Service.

For purposes of this Agreement, “Service” refers to the Company’s service which can be accessed via freemius.com and fully described here.

The terms “we,” “us,” and “our” refer to the Company. “You” refers to you, as a user of Service. By accepting our Privacy Policy and Terms of Use, you consent to our collection, storage, use and disclosure of your personal information as described in this Privacy.

## I. Information We Collect

We collect “Non-Personal Information” and “Personal Information.” Non-Personal Information includes information that cannot be used to personally identify you, such as anonymous usage data, general demographic information we may collect, referring/exit pages and URLs, platform types, preferences you submit and preferences that are generated based on the data you submit and number of clicks. Personal Information includes only your name and email, which you submit to us through the registration process at the Site.

### 1- Information collected via Technology

To activate the Service you do not need to submit any Personal Information other than your name and email address. To use the Service thereafter, you do not need to submit further Personal Information. However, in an effort to improve the quality of the Service, we track information provided to us by your browser or by our software application when you view or use the Service, such as the website you came from (known as the “referring URL”), the type of browser you use, the device from which you connected to the Service, the time and date of access, and other information that does not personally identify you. We track this information using cookies, or small text files which include an anonymous unique identifier. Cookies are sent to a user’s browser from our servers and are stored on the user’s computer hard drive. Sending a cookie to a user’s browser enables us to collect Non-Personal Information about that user and keep a record of the user’s preferences when utilizing our services, both on an individual and aggregate basis. For example, the Company may use cookies to collect the following information:

  * browser type
  * language preference
  * referring site
  * date and time of website visit
  * IP address

The Company may use both persistent and session cookies; persistent cookies remain on your computer after you close your session and until you delete them, while session cookies expire when you close your browser. You can configure your browser to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from any website you visit. If you do this, it’s possible that Freemius might not work as well. For complete information about our cookies policy please visit our Cookies Policy page.

### 2- Information you provide us by registering for an account 

In addition to the information provided automatically by your browser when you visit the Site, to become a subscriber to the Service you will need to create a personal profile. You can create a profile by registering with the Service and entering your email address, and creating a user name and a password. By registering, you are authorizing us to collect, store and use your email address in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

## II. How We Use And Share Information

**_Personal Information:_**

Except as otherwise stated in this Privacy Policy, we do not sell, trade, rent or otherwise share for marketing purposes your Personal Information with third parties without your consent. We do share Personal Information with our partners and vendors who are performing services for the Company, such as the servers for our email communications who are provided access to user’s email address for purposes of sending emails from us. Those vendors use your Personal Information only at our direction and in accordance with our Privacy Policy.

In general, the Personal Information you provide to us is used to help us communicate with you. For example, we use Personal Information to contact users in response to questions, solicit feedback from users, provide technical support, and inform users about promotional offers.

Additionally, the terms of the Data Processing Addendum available at https://freemius.com/terms/dpa/ shall apply to such Personal Information and be treated as an integral part of this privacy policy.

 ** _Non-Personal Information_**

In general, we use Non-Personal Information to help us improve the Service and customize the user experience. We also aggregate Non-Personal Information in order to track trends and analyze use patterns on the Site. This Privacy Policy does not limit in any way our use or disclosure of Non-Personal Information and we reserve the right to use and disclose such Non-Personal Information to our partners, advertisers and other third parties at our discretion.

In the event we undergo a business transaction such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of our assets, your Personal Information may be among the assets transferred. You acknowledge and consent that such transfers may occur and are permitted by this Privacy Policy, and that any acquirer of our assets may continue to process your Personal Information as set forth in this Privacy Policy. If our information practices change at any time in the future, we will post the policy changes to the Site so that you may opt out of the new information practices. We suggest that you check the Site periodically if you are concerned about how your information is used.

## III. How We Protect Information

We implement security measures designed to protect your information from unauthorized access. Your account is protected by your account password and we urge you to take steps to keep your personal information safe by not disclosing your password and by logging out of your account after each use. We further protect your information from potential security breaches by implementing certain technological security measures including encryption, firewalls and secure socket layer technology. However, these measures do not guarantee that your information will not be accessed, disclosed, altered or destroyed by breach of such firewalls and secure server software. By using our Service, you acknowledge that you understand and agree to assume these risks.

**Disclosures for National Security or Law Enforcement**  
Please note that under certain circumstances, we may be required to disclose your personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

## IV. Your Rights Regarding The Use Of Your Personal Information

You have the right at any time to prevent us from contacting you for marketing purposes. When we send a promotional communication to a user, the user can opt out of further promotional communications by following the unsubscribe instructions provided in each promotional e-mail. You can also indicate that you do not wish to receive marketing communications from us in the “Settings” section of the Site. Please note that notwithstanding the promotional preferences you indicate by either unsubscribing or opting out in the Settings section of the Site, we may continue to send you administrative emails including, for example, periodic updates to our Privacy Policy.

You may have the right to access personal data that we hold about you and request that we correct, amend, or delete it if it is inaccurate or processed in violation of the Privacy Policy. These access rights may not apply in some cases, including where providing access is unreasonably burdensome or expensive under the circumstances or where it would violate the rights of a third party. If you would like to request access to, correction, amendment, or deletion of your personal data, you can submit a written request to the contact information provided below. We may request specific information from you to confirm your identity.

## V. Your Right To Be Forgotten

You have the right to request for the erasure of your personal data off of our servers. Once such a request is made by you (please contact us at: [privacy@freemius.com](mailto:privacy@freemius.com)) we will be committed to carry out the erasure procedure as soon as possible.  
Please note that:

  1. Even after the erasure procedure is complete, your personal data will continue to reside in our backup archives for another 3 weeks. The reason for that is that it’s inoperable for us to isolate individual personal data within the entire archive.
  2. You can rest assured that your personal data will not be restored back into the production systems (except in certain rare instances, e.g., the need to recover from a natural disaster or from a serious security breach). In such cases, your personal data may be restored from backups, but the controller will take the necessary steps to honor the initial request and erase the primary instance of that data once again.
  3. Any backup archives which contain personal data are protected by strong encryption. Therefore, even if criminals were able to steal the archive, its contents would still remain inaccessible to them.
  4. Records of all data subject requests regarding their personal data will be retained, as will audit logs that record all activities on backup archives containing personal data. This means that the user can be confident that their personal data has been backed up in accordance with GDPR principles of security by design and by default, as well as data minimization, and that their rights, including the right to be forgotten, have been honored.

## VI. Links To Other Websites

As part of the Service, we may provide links to or compatibility with other websites or applications. However, we are not responsible for the privacy practices employed by those websites or the information or content they contain. This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by us through the Site and the Service. Therefore, this Privacy Policy does not apply to your use of a third party website accessed by selecting a link on our Site or via our Service. To the extent that you access or use the Service through or on another website or application, then the privacy policy of that other website or application will apply to your access or use of that site or application. We encourage our users to read the privacy statements of other websites before proceeding to use them.

## VII. Changes To Our Privacy Policy

The Company reserves the right to change this policy and our Terms of Service at any time. We will notify you of significant changes to our Privacy Policy by sending a notice to the primary email address specified in your account or by placing a prominent notice on our site. Significant changes will go into effect 30 days following such notification. Non-material changes or clarifications will take effect immediately. You should periodically check the Site and this privacy page for updates.

If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy or the practices of this Site, please contact us by sending an email to [privacy@freemius.com](mailto:privacy@freemius.com).

 _ **Last Updated: This Privacy Policy was last updated on May 24, 2015.**_
